

SIDDHARTH GARG

Developer, Al Engineer, CFA - Passed level 1

- @ i@siddharthgarg.in
- **♥** Hyderabad, India | Remote (Preferred)
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidg510/

EDUCATION

Btech, Computer Science | VIT Vellore (Institute of Eminence)

- ****** 07/2018 06/2022
- ▼ Vellore, India
- CGPA: 9.07

12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination(AISSCE) | Delhi Public School, RK Puram

- ****** 07 2015 05 2017
- New Delhi, India
- Score: 90%

10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC) | Delhi Public School, Agra

- 2015
- New Delhi, India
- CGPA: 9.4

TECH STACK

Programming

Python | SQL | JavaScript | C++ | C | Java

AI/ML

Image Recognition CNNs Sentiment Analysis

RNNs Topic Modeling Object Detection

Web Development

Django Flask NodeJS PHP ReactJS

UI/UX

 Illustrator
 Canva
 Adobe XD
 Photoshop

CERTIFICATIONS



Cleared Level 1 of Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Examination

TensorFlow Developer Certificate
Google's TensorFlow Developer Certificate

Skydiving
Tandem Skydiving Certificate, Pattaya

Consecutive First Prize, RCPC 2020 and 2019 Coding Competition, involving severalrounds by ACM, VIT

ABOUT ME

Started learning to write code when I was 12 years old, there was no going back from there. I enjoy my work, let it be Tech, Design or Finance, I love exploring different disciplines and developing solutions, that create value. Love to travel, been to (almost) everywhere in the country.

EXPERIENCE

Member Tech | DE Shaw India

i Jan 2022 – 5 Mar 2024 (LWD)

Acquired in-depth Finance and Technical knowledge in Fundamental equities team. Developed a framework from scratch for validating and reporting insights from multiple alternative data sources, reducing time from 1hr to 12mins.

Intern Member Tech | DE Shaw India

May 2021 - July 2021

Remote (Hyderabad Office)

Developed an extendible python application for tracking different internal tools' performance. Worked with Elastic, Logstash, Influx and Kibana.

Computer Vision Engineer | FindMind Analytics

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of clients' sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60% ______

Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer | ERIDE (NGO)

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Vellore, India

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education(ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy tounderprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, community centres to leading the NGO as a board member Creative Head | Mozilla Firefox Club VIT

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

Vellore, India

Oversaw the club's activities, mentored designers, guided junior members in technical projects.

Senior Core Committee Member, Tech | Computer Society of India, VIT

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

Vellore, India

Organized hackathons, lead workshops and programmed CTFs, with amazingly talented people I was fortunate enough to work with them on projects exposing students to new concepts.

PROJECTS

Malware Family classification using Convolutional Neural Networks on Byte Sequences

GUI based End to End Auto ML dashboard for object detection and masking. | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents using image processing and object detection | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hourDebates from different news channels

TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) | ## | 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack